Oṃ vasudevasutaḿ devaḿ kaḿsa-cāṇūra-mardanam devakī-paramānandaḿ kṛṣṇaḿ vande jagadgurum Oṃ
Adorations to Lord Kṛṣṇa; the Preceptor of the Universe;
Destroyer of the forces of Darkness and bestower of immortality;
Śrīmad Bhagavad Gītā in chapter 3 verse number 30. This chapter is
known as karma yoga. Yoga of action. Always remember you have four yogas. Karma yoga,
yoga of action. Yoga relating to your feelings called yoga for devotion. Bhakti
yoga. yoga relating to the willing movement of the mind. Dhyāna yoga. Yoga of meditation
and yoga that relates to your intellect, reasoning, understanding that's called jñāna yoga
to figure out which yoga you want to practice.
Can practice any one of the four, but always understand that all the four are always together.
Just like in your personality, you can highlight your hand,
you can highlight your heart, highlight your neck, highlight your head.
Whichever you may highlight, all the others follow it.
So this make it simple. This is called sura yoga or integral yoga. So with that
broad understanding of integral yoga, focus your attention on karma action
first to understand what we mean by action. Whatever you do by your thoughts that the
basis of your karma action. Action has three forms. Thought word lead
to a broader understanding.
No one can live without karma even for a single second.
Even when you say I'm not doing going to do any
work that the time you are doing more work than you ever imagined.
Therefore all these points have been made clear before.
Now the question arises always before a person
to understand the difference between svadharma and paradharma.
Swadharma is that which is in harmony with your personality and with your spiritual evolution
and you are born with it.
For example, led by your karmic process. You come into a family, you have father, mother.
Once you look at your father and mother,
now you don't have any choice. I should have another set of
starts.
That doesn't mean that you you disrespect other parents,
but your practical life depends upon your parents. In the same way you come with
certain karmic tendencies because your actions have not started just in this life. KMAS have
gone on through many lives. No two children in a family have the same karma. Ask the mothers.
One may be may have that inclination for arts. Another may have inclination
for mathematics and one may be a genius etc. So similarly every soul has come with
karma. Karma in a broad sense is of three types. Sañcita karma which
means accumulated storehouse of karma that karma exists in your causal plane.
It's it's an abstract. It's a very advanced technology.
Kas from millions of lives have accumulated and they are all recorded there. But they don't impact
on you at all. You don't know it. But out of all those sitas, a portion, just a little pinch,
has been the cause of your present embodiment. That pinch of karma that
has created your present embodiment is called prārabdha fructifying karma. Fructifying karma
determines plans out three things. Jati Aayua. Jati means in what family will you be born?
Your personality must match up with a family where there will be right type of influence.
If you are a musician, you be drawn to a family or even be before you open your eyes. In other words,
when open your eyes, you see musical instruments around you. Maybe a flute,
maybe a something else, piano or whatever. Even prior to that, even before you open your eyes,
you are listening to music. Father has been playing piano or whatever. So the idea is that
you are drawn to a family because of your praabda. Next point,
what type of body will you have and how long will you live?
That also is
well planned in a divine way. That's called au how long you are going to live and boa boa
means pleasure and pain experiences of joy and sorrow prosperity and adversity and in every
life you have experience of joy and sorrow. No one's life is just all happiness just like
You experience day and night.
It is not just perpetual day unless you are in po
and you enjoy to have day and night. Similarly, joy and sorrow.
The quantity and the quality of those vogas they depend upon your kmas.
While this has been already planned,
sketched out in your as you live your life you improve upon the basic sketch.
Just like a painter has wants to bring out some art, piece of art,
he himself doesn't know what it will look like in the end. So he starts putting some lines. Outlines
praabdai is the outline just a little sketch. Your effort what you do now in this life you
are building upon the basis of that sketch and you have the possibility to make the
sketch turn into divine. No matter how it was in the basic stage or make it demonic your
purusha your self effort can bring out divine in you. You can blossom or you can stay thorn.
The goal before you is no matter whatever prārabdha you may have
allow your mind to become involved in satsanga
be inspired to follow spiritual path and develop a deep understanding that you can
you are not dependent on kmas so don't go after asking astrologers what type of karma I had in
the past. No matter whatever kmas you have the possibility of turning those karmas. If
suppose you have lot of adversity try to bring a spirit of austerity while facing adversity count
upon your faith. Develop strength of faith. Get involved with satsanga etc. So ultimately your
adversity that was based on a negative karma now has led you to develop spiritual association. It
has led you to gain deeper insight into the goal of life. It has speeded your spiritual movement.
So it doesn't matter what whatever might have been the cause that created your
negative karma but you have the ability to turn it turn into it into your favor.
Likewise suppose some good karmas of the past has brought you lot of prosperity unimaginable
not a single day of rest always something drawing you to wonderful
things come to waterfalls come to the Himalayas lots of invitations
I'm just making up joke but idea what that's
bad. The prosperity keeps your mind moving around this fact.
Why? Because you did good kas.
You can utilize your prosperity and become more prosperous, more more enriched in a spiritual
way. And most people during prosperity, they become vain. And after that good karma
of the past is over, they have they find themselves tumbling into a lesser plane.
So their good karma of the past has proven negative
all that again is allegorical what I'm saying
I'm not condoning negative kmas but no matter whatever your karmas might have
been in the past you are the architect of your destiny that point is being hammered on you And
therefore do not let your mind become just in a state of despair but rather hold on to that
inner in inspiration that you have the potential to to change your karma and
your goal is to attain self-reization. So while I was talking about sit karma
accumulated storehouse a pinch of it gave you prārabdha prārabdha you
modify develop on that prārabdha by your self effort the new kmas
that are generated now on the basis of your praabda they are called karma current karma
Current karma goes in two directions. One aspect of current karma may join
your parabdha and bear fruit within this lifetime.
Another aspect certain karma you do and you don't get the result in
this life. Why? Because there are many karmas lined up in a queue.
So every kva doesn't have the opportunity to get the result. Many of your good kmas
line up you did meditation today lot of japa the result of that karma should be
should give you happiness doesn't come today comes five days later.
I'm trying to give in a simple way to understand
embellishing your praabda and creating a basis for future embodiment.
But if you have started practicing karma yoga now you are
moving towards karma yoga means by performing your actions
you're purifying your heart. action karma for chittashudi purity of heart. As heart is purified,
devotion begins to develop. You are not your love is directed towards God,
not towards your ego. Your ego becomes inferior. God becomes the highlight.
Meditation begins to develop and deep insight begins to develop insight into who am I.
All this implies that you are once karma has turned to karma yoga you
are moving towards enlightenment liberation.
If you attain liberation, liberation is attain attained during your lifetime. Your goal is not
to keep it in future but always the goal is to become enlightened. Becoming enlightened again has
has two implications. Suppose you are climbing a mountain. You have to go to the top. In the early
state of your movement, your climbing process is defective. You climb and then you fall down. Go up
and down and up and down and sometimes you break your legs. So it takes time to again go on to fly.
Next stage comes
you go on climbing but there are down downfalls
and and when you get into the trap of downfall it will delay you etc.
Third type you have come to you become so skilled that falling back is impossible. Moving up that's
the only one way left. The moment you have come to that state you are called enlightened.
No matter where you are because we have only one way to go.
So you go on moving towards like a river that has come close to the ocean and has up on a
mountain looking down into the ocean. Nose is already moving towards now for the river
to enter the ocean. It has no other choice but to dissolve in ocean. It is enlightened.
Similarly, you become when you become enlightened.
All kmas are burnt up. All sit karmmas that could have given you millions and trillions
of embodiment and still they will not be exhausted because you go on adding karmas.
But entire karma storehouse burns upd
mystical way. If it got burnt up literally your body will suddenly vanish the moment
you attain liberation. People will be extremely afraid of
You hear the news, they came to the
vanished
and the a newspaper says they all attain liberation.
Liberation is not vanishing of the physical body.
Inwardly you are not the body. Your body has become your cell phone.
You are not confined to the body. You just like a wave. Wave remains a wave and yet it can have
the attunement I am the ocean. Once you have reached that that's that's called liberation.
All these scriptures have been given by liberated sages. If they
were liberated and vanished, there will be no scriptures.
Having surrendered all actions to me with your mind illumined by spiritual vision,
you should fight without desire free from the sense of mindness and the de and devoid
of the fever of mental worries. No, this is highly condensed writing.
Having surrendered all actions to me.
How to attain enlightenment. Certain points have been already discussed before. Understand
the importance of sadharma. Actions that have come to you by your very nature.
If you have you are inclined to mathematics get ahead. If you are inclined to artistic
painting etc or music etc then move ahead in that direction. That's I'm speaking broadly
from another point of view. No matter whatever type of duty you are doing in divine plan,
everyone is placed in certain situations, circumstances where where you whether you
like it or not, you have to go do certain things and certain chores of life. When you do that,
don't do it with a sense of disgust. cursing yourself and your fate but do it with a sense
that it is divinely planned situation. How fortunate am I because God is going to make
me do it even though I don't find all the strength behind but God is there with that
faith and trust and with a sense of respect towards whatever duty you do not disgust.
Just like whatever food you eat, if you eat it with disgust, it's going to create digestion.
If you face your karma with disgust, it's going to create negative situations.
So that subtle point has to be understood. But now
raise the level of understanding.
Doing your duties.
A profounder
purpose behind it is to develop
that understanding that God is working through me. Who am I? It's not ego that accomplishes anything.
Even just digesting food, ego can't do it.
that the profound goal has to be in view. Go on building up that sense that God is working through
me. I am an instrument in divine hand and every action I am doing is a form of worship of God.
It is to please God. You are doing the action not to please the ego.
Ego is a monkey when it is pleased. The monkey that rides on your neck
when it is pleased it chokes your neck displeased.
It chokes it also both ways cuz both ways legs around your death.
So having surrendered so actions to be done with a spirit of surrender to God. That's a
broad understanding of karma yoga with your mind illumined by spiritual vision. Another
term is used.
Whatever work you do, do it with vaudi with a
with a discriminative with a mind that knows the difference between
right and wrong. Between good and just that which seems pleasant but not good. Between and prayer.
Sha that which uplifts you. Prayer that remains pleasant but degrades you. The mind that knows
that type of difference. That type of mind you must develop while you are doing your duties.
And you develop it. If you are practicing daily sadhana like japa, meditation,
satsanga, as you go on doing that, automatically
your movement in daily life, your conduct in daily life is
guided by discerning intellect. No matter what situation you are,
you will not outstep
the limits of righteousness.
In other words, no matter whatever situation you are,
you will not do something for which you may have to regret.
This is again ideal. Ideal means you go on failing, you go on making mistakes,
but don't pat on your back how wonderful you are.
Always understand mistakes are mistakes and not to regret about the mistakes too much only you
should move ahead. So many mistakes you have overcome and this you are going to overcome.
That's called first point using vaudi in your life. So that recognize what error did you
commit which you should not commit again? What lessons have you learned which you should use?
And therefore day by day you are learning improving moving towards God
and all actions to be offered to God. That point I have already explained.
Third point
means without expectations
in common
parlance when the people talk together. The word nasha is pathetic word. Asha
expectation. Nasha being expectationless.
It brings sadness in the heart.
But your goal is to become nash. All ashas, all expectations must move away. As long as
there are not perfect. A river flows on there is expectation enters the ocean
full. All that you expect in the past, present and future all is fulfilled.
Then you are nasha
dev of all expectations and desires.
That should be your goal.
the sense of me and mine. Therefore,
mantras always have that. The subtle implication is nothing
neither mean nor mine
and you should fight. People understand the term
Luchand you will ask poor person how is life and the Spanish language says
The term fight it doesn't mean real fight. The entire story of
life moving towards God. Realization. Fight is
between the higher forces of light and forces of darkness.
compassion, understanding, humility. They come with divine appearance,
divine garbs and chant they go and fight.
Allow that fight to go on day by day. Then your life is wonderful. Then you are living
goes on telling
fight but not with fever. Fever of the body or fever of the mind.
Not with mental stress. The term Sanskrit terms are shoka and moa. Not with grief or delusion.
Then your fight will be a movement of spiritual progress. It will a form of festivity.
It will not be
degrading, humiliating. You will not be defeated. Is a fight that
is actually a celebration of your coming victory.
Those
who are endowed with faith and are free from the voice of finding fault with my
teachings. They too attain freedom from all actions by following the path revealed by me.
Now two points are there. People listen to
certain teachings intellectually they grasp they can repeat the teachings
but in practice they won't do it.
Then there are others they may not repeat all that
but they have their heart has felt the joy of listening and faith has entered.
So therefore a person of faith may not have listened all but whatever the fa person of
faith listens to is effective. It's going to be digested. It will bring you spiritual
nourishment. So therefore it doesn't matter if you have not understood all these teachings.
or you don't possess the knowledge that the intellectuals possess. Don't compare with
them. Move by faith. Faith gives you a greater guarantee for your spiritual movement than your
rational intellectual understanding. That doesn't mean that you shouldn't have understanding.
You have to understand the difference between theoretical knowledge and practical knowledge.
There is saying an house of practice is better than tons of theory.
When you have faith in what you have heard that allows you to practice,
you may be practicing only an ounce. Another person has accumulated tons
of theory but there isn't a house of practice who is better the one who has
faith based movement that's what Kṛṣṇa is saying those who are endowed with faith
and free from the voice of finding fault with my teachings
You may not have all the teaching but don't find fault with it.
And having mentioned one vice you are actually called upakana is pointing
out the group of vices all that is called mala kama crodha loha moa
mada matsara all that is implied if you have the malas gross impurities
faith within you cannot be active
So your faith must
have a fashion
must be equipped with these gonas. These divine qualities,
qualities of absence of anger, humility, gentleness, sincerity, all good virtues.
But those who do not follow my teachings and are afflicted with the voice of finding fault
blow them to be dullwitted and deluded in every form of knowledge. They are
heading towards their own destruction. Those who do not follow my teachings,
what is my teachings? Perform all actions with the spirit of surrender to God.
That's the central per central essence of the teachings.
All your duties with shadi.
Your heart must have faith that you are worshiping God through your duties and God is going to
respond to you because your relationship with God is like a child's relationship
with a mother and a child has tremendous faith.
may figure that out.
That type of relationship must develop
and
mind that that develops always a sense of contradiction, a sense of jealousy.
sense of opposition.
Instead of that develop mind that trusts faith
is characterized byia is called jealousy. Matsara.
Matsar term is not only you are jealous but your mind is buzzing
with lots of defects in people like so many mosquitoes buzz over you
and you don't find rest. You go to a wonderful picturesque setting of nature, wonderful lake.
Everywhere is something so delightful. But suddenly a swarm of mosquitoes very small little
they're called maturk
word mats
certain negative way of thinking that goes on buzzing over you
in such a way all the beauty and glory and grace of God goes away
and the world becomes joyous for it. People are wonderful. The world is
joyous. The breeze blows with divine grace. Sun shines with joy. The ocean surges with
joy. And all is beckoning your soul to its highest attainment. They all
welcoming you. They live for you. They are working for you. They exist for you.
But if that ishavi then you are moving that way.
Then your thoughts are constantly creating perverted desires, anger, sama, croha,
loha, greed, moa, delusion, man, pride, matsaria. this mosquito type of jealous.
So if you have that sodha and are moving away from this matsara, you are going to
attain the goal. But those who don't have it, they are heading towards their own destruction.
What do we mean by destruction?
The term destruction is used in a figurative way. Soul cannot be destroyed. That's
figurative way. It is used that your self effort becomes as if dead. If you are not aware of your
self effort, you are unable to exercise your self effort, then you are living in vain.
You will again come back to it. But nature will have to take lot
of time to bring you back into that situation. You go through many lives
conditioning the object.
It means your your mind is hugging the object. It's a mental
mental phenomenon sa
if attachment has developed in your mind. Now the mind is restless unless it gets the object
and it is an impossible task. Object is not a reality point of view and object has not been
the source of your happiness. So you is a wrong pursuit. But nevertheless follow the story.
This mental dependence, mental attachment causes desires. Mind is restless. So it has
to have so many desires to fulfill it to cure the restlessness. But running after
desires and fulfilling them doesn't really cure. It enhances the rest.
While you are trying to fulfill your desires,
two possibilities are there. Things oppose the fulfillment. Then you become angry, agitated
and another your desires are fulfilled. Sometimes many fantast
That creates agitation.
When desire is not fulfilled,
it creates agitation. When is fulfilled, it creates agitation.
Understand?
When your mind is agitated, your intellect, your intellect is like
the flashlight. But if your sleeve is constantly agitated over your flashlight,
you can't handle it. Can't really use it.
That's called moa.
You are unable to see things in a healthy manner.
Let's see how situation. Let me repeat that.
You go on repeating the object in your mind. You become attached.
Attachment brings desire.
From anger.
Because of anger you get this delusion.
When you have your memory of what is right,
what is wrong has gone away. You don't even know what you are really looking for.
When that state has reached then in spite of the flashlight in your hand flashlight as
if doesn't work. So you're not guided by it. You're guided by the illusions of your mind.
In other words, you are unable to develop vive buddhi, a healthy intellect that sees
the difference between right and wrong, recognizes the right course. Once that has happened, you are
being led to destruction figuratively. That means all progress depends upon a healthy intellect.
But all this sequence has led the intellect to become as if dead. Allow the intellect
to be dead. Then you are going to be destroyed. Figurative language.
Live in such a way that this series of mistakes don't take place. And with this