Om Neelambuja Shyaamala Komalaangam
Sita Samaaropita Vaama Bhaa gam.
Paanow Mahasaayaka Chaaru Chaapam
Namami Ramam Raghuwansha Naatham.
Adorations to Lord Rama,
whose complexion is like a blue lotus,
who is very tender and delightful in appearance.
Sita is seated on his left side,
and he is carrying a powerful
bow and arrow in his hands.
We continue in Balakanda of Ramayana,
verses 31 onwards.
Swami Tulsidas, the author of the Ramayana,
is still in the process of introducing his work,
and that process itself is a
foundation of the Ramayana.
Presently, describing glory of the mantra ‘Rama.’
maṁtra mahāmani biṣāya byala ke,
meṭata kathina kuaṁka bhāla ke.
harana moha tama dinakara kara se,
sevaka sali pāla jaladhara se.
For removing the poison of
the snake of vishayarasa,
Rama is the great mantra and a mystical jewel.
When bitten by a snake, ancient people used to
recite mantras to neutralize this snake poison.
Also, they applied certain jewel that
was specially charged in a spiritual way—
that's an old time remedy for snake poison.
Here the snake poison is vishayarasa.
Try to understand ‘rasa’—'rasa' is taste.
You live in the world process
that has three planes:
Physical plane—bhur-loka.
The rasa of bhur-loka is gross—
the taste that you enjoy by eating wonderful food,
from restaurant to restaurant,
and drink, and all that.
That's one type of vishaya-rasa.
The second type of vishaya-rasa
goes into your feeling aspect.
Lots of imaginations, lot of mental
distractions caused by karma—desire.
And the third type of 'rasa' is intellectual.
When you discover how bright you are—
how good you feel. Positively or negatively,
whichever way,—that’s intellectual.
‘Rasa’ in all the three stages,
if you are not a devotee of God,
they are negative and they are like poison.
The only difference is poison kills you once,
vishayaras will go on killing you—
There's no limit.
The proof is you are here.
Imagine where have you been—
for the long time.
Every soul has gone through countless embodiments.
There was not a time when you didn't exist,
but how did you exist?
I'm not leading you into too much of that.
That also should not burden your mind.
Time is kind of a dream—it is not a reality.
So Vishayavyal, the snake of vishayaras—
vishayaras which I described in three stages—
and that snake has bitten the soul.
It's all allegorical.
The main purpose of your life, real purpose,
is to remedy this poison,
neutralize it before you end
your present personality.
And for this type of mystic snake that
has bitten you—for removing that poison—
Rama mantra is powerful, potent remedy.
In other words, if you do
japa with profound feeling,
and surrender to God,
your mind will begin
to develop taste for satsanga,
taste for developing virtuous qualities,
taste for ascending the heights of wisdom—
and all that.
Once that change has occurred—
from vishayaras to bhaktiras,
premaras, jnanaras, ras ras, rasovaisa—
that change is a real spiritual movement
in an aspirant—
shifting from lesser type of rasa to higher type—
until you go to the real rasa—raso vai saha.
“meṭata kathina kuaṁka bhāla ke.”
This also is a profound statement.
Rama mantra effaces—it’s a rubber that
deletes what's written on your skull.
The village people really believe—
they see a human skull and they
find some strange scratches on it.
They say that's bhagya is written there—
what the person was,
and what type of karmas he had done.
They are all given in a very
subtle manner,
in a mystical language.
But turn away from that simile I gave,
just to understand that
everyone is moved by karma.
We are born with, led by
prarabdha karma of the past.
Just to give you again a
rehashing of that subject.
Karma comes in three categories:
sanchita, prarabdha and kriyamana.
Kriyamana is also known as agami karma.
Sanchita is a total storehouse
and it cannot be counted.
Out of sanchita karma, only a pinch or a group—
a small group—matures into prarabdha
karma and that is the cause
of your present embodiment.
Prarabdha karma determines
for the soul three things:
Jati—what type of class of family
the soul must incarnate into.
Everything is well-planned from the divine source.
You don't get a baby in your
house just by accident.
But that is all a Divine plan.
And a baby inherits the good qualities,
as well as defects, of the
parents and the grandparents.
That also is based on karma.
Nothing has come by chance.
Jati is determined, the class is determined,
by prarabdha.
Ayu is determined by prarabdha.
Ayu is how long you are
going to live in that body.
No matter what may be.
People may go on saying,
“If only that medicine had been given,
the person would have lived more.”
It seems reasonable and there is no harm in that.
But the reality is,
if prarabdha has ended,
there is nothing in the
world that can prevent death.
And everyone is conditioned by that.
If it is not your prarabdha to die,
you may fall from 20-stories high building ,
and fall into a truck that
contains a lot of flowers.
But
if prarabdha has ended,
even just one cup of tea—between
the cup and the lip—
there occurs your end.
So jati, ayu and bhoga.
Another point, the general plot of your life—
how many days you will pass like spring,
how many days you will pass like rains,
how many days you will pass like a storm,
how many days you will pass like autumn.
I am giving you figurative language.
Just like seasons come, similarly,
you have seasons of karmic process.
And nobody is exempt from it.
“Deha dhare kaa dand hai sab kahoo ko hoy.”
Whether you are Rama, Krishna,
whether you are Jesus
—no matter who you are—
and all sages and saints—Ramakrishna Paramahamsa,
Ramana Maharshi, Swami Sivananda—
whomsoever,
the subject to disease, aging and death.
What I am describing is the bhoga,.
Bhoga refers to enjoyment.
The term enjoyment is little confusing.
In philosophical language,
if certain karma has given you a lot of torture,
in that language it is called,
“you are enjoying karma”—karma bhoga.
So no matter what you experience,
pleasure or pain,
they are the fructification of karma.
So, led by karma, every soul goes on
moving—from embodiment to embodiment.
That karma is as if written on the forehead.
That karma—you are stamped
with that karmic process.
Unstamp it, delete it.
How can you do that?
Create a brush with the Divine name Rama.
And start applying it again and again.
I am using figurative language.
Turn to Ram Japa—
Divine name Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama.
Or complete mantra:Om Sri Ramayanama,
Om Sri Ramayanama.
Or the mantra into which you are initiated.
All mantras are Rama mantra.
And that Rama mantra removes that what is written,
as it were, by your karmic process.
And that aspect of creation is handled by Brahma,
the creator.
So whatever Brahma has written down on your lalat—
your skull is called lalat—that will be effaced.
And let your lalat shine, being free of karmas.
In other words, the moment you have developed
aspiration for attaining enlightenment,
faith, and profound understanding,
that the real you is not the body—
The real you is eternal Atma, the Self—
If that has started blossoming in your heart—
that type of feeling—
you have cut down the karmic chain.
“harana moha tama dinakara kara se.”
And for removing the darkness of moha—
moha is delusion, infatuation.
But here it refers to ignorance
itself—avidya, the source of moha.
Sometimes what's known as upalakshana, a word is
used, but you don't take it exactly as the word,
but where the word is pointing to.
The word moha has been used in this,
but it's pointing to avidya.
And for removing harana moha tama,
moha is described as darkness.
Dinakara—dinakara refers to the sun.
That's like the rays of the sun destroy darkness,
Rama mantra destroys ignorance.
And for sustaining and nourishing devotees—
devotees are described like paddy field.
Rama mantra is like the cloud that gives rain.
Just like a cloud comes,
all the paddy field enjoys.
If you are in tune with japa and develop
profound success in your practice sadhana,
then that type of joy awaits you.
All that you do is simply sit down, relax,
let your mind recite the mantra,
and allow your feeling to bring you to that state—
that you are like in the paddy field.
And the mantra brings you nectary nourishment.
You can go one step further.
Imagine you are the peacock.
Rama mantra brings you rain,
and you are spreading your feathers—
and the feathers are shining.
abhimata dāni devataru bara se,
sevata sulabha sukhada hari hara se.
sukabi sarada nabha mana uḍaganase,
rāmabhagata jana jīvana dhana se.
The divine mantra is like kalpaka tree,
a mystic tree that gives you anything you wish.
All that you have to do is come close to the tree,
sit under the tree, and wish.
That's called kalpaka tree.
The real kalpaka tree allows your
mind to be in tune with God's will.
In one word, it is God realization.
But, God realization fulfills
all your desires at once,
and your entire mind itself is transcended.
While you are moving to God realization,
you go on experiencing increasing contentment—
real fulfillment of your wishes, your desires—
until all desires move away.
So Rama mantra is that type of kalpaka tree that
will bestow upon you anything that you wish.
Of course you must realize,
once you are repeating Rama mantra,
you have no choice but to wish
for that which is profound.
Because the very Rama mantra
will change your intellect.
Without Rama mantra,
your intellect goes after
little things, petty things.
With Rama mantra,
your intellect develops
sensitivity for higher things—
things of value, things of virtue.
Two things will happen:
Purity of your heart,
that will allow you to have aspiration—
not ordinary desire;
and fulfillment of that aspiration.
And they play the role of Rama mantra—
the two aspects: Ra and Ma.
They are like Hari and Hara.
For a devotee, Rama mantra plays the
role of Shiva and Vishnu put together.
That again is a profound implication.
Alankara Priyo Vishnu, Abhisheka Priya Shiva.
If you are aVishnu devotee—that’s
first to understand in a profound way.
In your spiritual movement,
first stage of your progress
is developing divine qualities—
called daivi sampat:
Fearlessness, humility,
charity, absence of vanity—
and all these great qualities.
The more you develop them,
the more you are invoking Lord Vishnu.
Lord Vishnu is pleased by ornaments.
These are the ornaments—Alankara Priyo.
You are developing them but it is like as if
you are putting those ornaments on Lord Vishnu,
because deep down you are Lord Vishnu—Divine.
So Vishnu's grace continues to
deck you with divine qualities.
And that Lord Vishnu is called Hari.
Hari is figuratively—in a very profound way.
He plays the role of being a thief.
He enables you to develop profound feeling,
which is like butter.
You churn butter and He’s waiting.
Once the butter has been churned,
your ego will not get it.
Your vishaya-vasana will not go after it.
Krishna will come and steal it.
Hardly you will know who ate it.
What happened to all your sadhana?
There is a stealthy movement leading to a
profound transformation in your personality—
without your knowing.
You are simply doing your
Integral Yoga day by day,
and a deep down change goes on occurring—
stealthily.
Sometimes you are sleeping and you are getting
more and more enriched in a spiritual way.
Lord Shiva's role is like a robber.
He doesn't steal—
he doesn't wait for you.
But when you have brought the climax,
you have developed—
you have removed mala, vikshepa,
and your ego has been practically effaced.
Now Shiva comes with his trishul,
and sucks up all your vasanas, all your ignorance.
What is being said is:
Vishnu’s role is in the early stage of sadhana.
Shiva's role in the climax state of sadhana.
The same Vishnu is Shiva.
The same Shiva is Vishnu.
In the storyline,
they are devotees of each other.
So, when you serve Lord Rama,
or become devotee of Rama mantra,—
then Rama mantra plays the role of Hari and Hara—
Vishnu and Shiva.
Rama mantra decks you with divine qualities,
and Shiva brings in your mind absolute sannyasa—
and that's the goal of life.
Therefore, in Indian culture, even royalty—
when they had to fight against enemies—
the army used to repeat “Haro Hara, Haro Hara.”
It's a figurative language.
Life is a battle.
In that battle, bring the slogan “Haro Hara,”
create divine virtues leading to absolute—
nothing exists, nothing belongs to me.
If you have achieved that,
then you have attained real victory.
sakala sukṛta phala bhūri bhogase,
No—still there are some more points left.
The divine name Rama is like stars shining
in the blue sky in the autumn season.
In Sharad Ritu when the sky is cloudless,
you see the stars shining.
Your mind… With Rama mantra, your mind becomes
so purified that when you relax with your mind,
you are as if enjoying a starry sky—
twinkle twinkle little stars.
For the devotees of Rama,
Rama mantra is all their possessions,
all their wealth.
sakala sukṛta phala bhūri bhogase,
jaga hita nirupadhi sādhu loga se.
sevaka mana mānasa marāla se,
pāvana gaṁga taraṁga māla se.
Rama mantra brings about fructification of
all your good karmas.
This allegorical term.
Any good karma has a limited fructification,
but Rama mantra creates such mystical
type of good karma that the joy arising
out of—the fructification arising out
of that karma—is of a profound nature.
In simple terms, try to understand,
if you are rajasic, your joy will depend
upon how many things have you attained,
how many things you have achieved.
If you are satvic, your joy is
how closer you are coming to God,
the joy of turning your mind into
the sky with twinkling stars.
And Rama mantra is a benefactor,
like saints and sages,
they are benefactors of the world.
Rama mantra is constant benefactor,
because as you recite the Rama mantra,
and worship Rama and surrender to him,
a total change begins to occur
deep in your personality.
That Rama brings about a great transformation,
and Rama mantra is like a swan in
the mental lake of his devotees.
It’s allegorical.
If you look at a lake, and
lake looks a little boring,
but look at the swans swimming in the lake,
it brightens up.
The mind is like the lake Manasasovar,
and Rama mantra becomes like a swan.
It brings about a great transformation,
a great change in your mind.
Or the mind enjoys Rama mantra in a profound way.
And among purifiers,
Rama mantra is like taranga malas of Ganga
—the waves of Ganges river.
kupatha kutaraka kucāli
kali kapaṭa daṁbha pāṣaṁda,
dahana rāma guna grāma jimi
iṁdhana anala pracaṁḍa. 32(A).
Rama mantra is the bestower of all divine virtues—
the entire daivi sampat—
and remover of negative qualities,
which are known as asuri sampat.
Kumarga—asuri qualities are
described moving on a wrong path.
One path is satsanga. another
is opposed to satsanga—kusanga.
The path leading to kusanga is kumarga.
The path leading to satsanga is sanamarga.
Kutaraka— wrong type of reasoning.
This is called asuri sampat.
The example of kutaraka—
a tiger was drinking water from
a river—from a mountain river.
Unwittingly, without thinking,
a deer comes without knowing that
tiger was nearby,
started drinking.
And the tiger, whose mind has become activated
by seeing the deer, says to the deer,
"How dare you let me drink the water
that you have sipped,—juta water?"
The deer said, "Oh Sir, the water is coming from
you to me, so I am not giving you juta water."
Then he said, "Oh, forget about it.
But why did your father say
abusive words towards me?"
The deer had no answer.
So this is called kutaraka.
You create your own rationality to achieve
what you want to achieve egoistically,
and there is no real reasoning behind it.
This is called brute logic.
These are demoniac qualities—
kupatha—wrong path,
kutaraka—wrong logic,
kuchal—wrong conduct,
and kapata—deceptive movement.
And I will not deal with it
because everybody knows it.
You know the enemies can pretend to be so loving,
but all their love and all their words are wicked—
kapat yukt, deceptive
and pakhanda, hypocrisy.
Asuri sampat:
dambho darpo ’bhimānaśh cha
krodhaḥ pāruṣhyam eva cha
ajñānaṁ chābhijātasya pārtha sampadam āsurīm
In the Gita in the 16th chapter,
you have the description of daivi sampat
and asuri sampat.
The asuri sampat has been described.
Dambho—deceptive, darpo—conceit,
abhiman—egotistic, krodha—anger,
parushyam—speaking very harsh, bitter words.
They all arise out of ajnana because
they are never going to do good to you,
but your ignorance doesn't
allow you to understand.
Daivi sampat, contrasted from asuri sampat:
abhayam—fearlessness. All this I am saying quickly
and they are to be attained by sustained effort—
no matter how long it takes.
And your success is never absolute,
there is always degrees of success,
but an effort directed in the right direction—no
matter how little progress
you make—is substantial.
How to stay fearless—
that you have to work upon it.
The main answer is:
if you keep yourself involved under good guidance,
practice integral yoga in your daily life,
abhayam—fearlessness—will
enter your heart by degrees,
until the fearlessness becomes enormous.
And if that happens,
you are enlightened, you are liberated.
Steadiness in Jnana and Yoga.
Steadiness in practicing
vichar—that’s what is meant by jnana.
Vichar means affirmation—“Who am I? I
am not the body, I am not the
mind, I am not the intellect,
I am Satchidananda— existence,
knowledge, bliss, absolute”.
And Yoga. The term Yoga in this
context is meditation—directing
your mind to the practice of
concentration, meditation.
Also, another term is used, upasana,
directing your mind to love of God.
Danam—developing the quality of being charitable,
a charitable personality.
\You should be like a sandalwood tree.
Not only you are charitable to
people who come praising you,
but you are charitable even to
people who come to cut you down.
Don't take it too literally.
But the idea—that’s where goodness
reaches a divine stage—a goodness that
brings the head off the most terrible
personalities—brings the head down.
And the victory that you attain by goodness—
that victory is yours and it is perfect.
But any victory attained by deceptive method—
by cruelty and so forth—
that victory is extremely…
it's just like you created a wonderful
pudding but pushed in some worms.
All these negative qualities that I described—
they’re called asuri sampat—
they are destroyed by Rama nama,
just like fuel is burnt down by fire.
rāmacarita rākesa kara sarisa sukhada saba kāhu,
sajjana kumuda cakora cita
hita biseṣi bara lāhu. 32(B).
The glorious story of Rama—Ramacharitra—
all the conduct of Rama, all his righteous deeds,
all the story of Rama is known as Ramacharitra.
Ramacharitra is like the purnima—full moon—
showering nectarine rays on all.
Sarve bhavantu sukinah—May all be happy,
that type of divine will emanates from
Ramacharitra.
Those who are sajjans,
those who are already devotees,
who enjoy satsanga,
they are like lotuses—closed lotuses.
Ramacharitra makes the lotus blossom.
Or they are like chakora birds—
again and again Indian literature is filled
with a type of bird that stays on a tree,
and becomes so fascinated by the
moon, that it goes into ecstasy.
Ram mantra and Ramcharitmanas—the
Ramcharitra, that's what happens
to your chit—the heart within you,
that becomes like chakor, it enters to ecstasy.
kīnhi prasna jehi bhiti bhavānī,
jehi bidhi samkara kahā bakhānī.
so saba hetu kahaba mat gāī,
kathāprabaṁdha bicitra banāī.
The manner in which Parvati Devi asked questions—
asked of Shiva—that story is coming,
very engrossing and very profound.
And Lord Shiva narrated this story extensively.
And all that story I am going to
relate to you through this Ramayana.
jeht yaha kathā sunī nahi hoī,
jani ācaraju karai suni soī.
kathā alaukika sunahi je gyānī,
naht ācaraju karahi asa jānī.
Now, Tulsidasji is also
pointing out to the fact that,
when you read the Ramayana,
many passages or many of the stories,
don't agree with Valmiki Ramayana.
Valmiki Ramayana has done the
same thing in a different way.
And some stories are totally
different from Valmiki Ramayana.
The fact is, Ramayana writing
is not a historical writing.
It's an allegorical mystic writing.
Mystic writing is done by sages according
to the need of the people they face.
So those subtle details we will describe later.
But at this stage, Valmiki's Ramayana is more
focused on non-dual Vedanta, JnanaPradhan.
Tulsi Ramayana is Bhakti Pradhan—
more focused on devotion.
Valmiki Ramayana ends up with Rama being alone.
Even Sita—Rama worked so hard for attaining Sita—
Even that Sita goes away from Rama—ultimately.
Tulsi Ramayana doesn't handle that,
but simply says—Rama and Sita enjoy forever.
So if you are too foxy in your mind,
you'll go on asking “Which is better,
Tulsi Ramayana or Valmiki Ramayana?”
If you happen to read other Ramayanas, they tell
the story in another way,—a totally different way.
Many engrossing stories are
there in other Ramayanas,
which Tulsi Ramayana doesn't have.
And Tulsidasji says “Do not wonder about it.”—
If you read this Ramayana and it doesn't
tally with your concept of what you
have read, don't wonder about it.
kathā alaukika sunahi je gyānī—those who
are wise, they hear stories that are alokik.
Alokik implies something totally new.
And they do not wonder
about those stories because—
In other words, for enlightened mind,
the same katha—the same story of Rama—
no two enlightened persons will say the story
exactly the same ,because each enlightened
one looks at his audience and reaches out
to the audience according to their need.
And in doing so, he has absolute freedom.
He can make Rama cross a river—
even in Balakanda, where he is
going to Ayodhya to marry Sita.
Valmiki has allowed Rama to cross a
river and all the joy of devotees.
Tulsidasji makes him wait.
He crosses when he is in the forest.
All these are minor and major changes.
rāmakathā kai miti jaga nāhī,
asi pratīti tinha ke mana māhī.
nānā bhāti rāma avatārā,
rāmāyana sata koṭi apārā.
rāmakathā kai miti jaga nāhī—
There is no count of how many
variations of Ramakatha exist.
Without my going into details,
a direct understanding—all souls are Rama—
and each soul, what you have gone through,
what awaits you in future is Ramakatha.
Count Ramakathas—how many are there?
Miti jaga nāhī. There is no count.
Once you understand Ramakatha in that sense,
you are moving towards wisdom.
Nānā bhāti rāma avatārā—
Rama as avatara appeared
in the world in countless manners.
Rāmāyana sata koṭi apārā.
Shata koṭi—koti is more than a million.
Mathematically, probably it is 10 million or so.
But forget about mathematics.
Shata koti—millions and millions types.
Million by million type.
So many are Ramayanas.
Which Ramayana you want to read?
Every soul is Rama, and all that is experienced
by the soul from bondage to release is Ramayana.
And with this I will conclude.
Om Shri Ramayana, Om Namah Shivaya.
Om Shanti, Shanti, Shanti.