Namaste everyone, today we will study the profound teachings of Kṛṣṇa
from the Bhagavad Gita chapter 2 about dharma and the eternal soul
Kṛṣṇa tells Arjuna in verse 2 47, karmany eva adhikaram te
ma phaleshu kadachana, you have the right to perform actions but never
to the fruits of action, this is the essence of nishkama karma
the concept of ahimsa, non-violence, is fundamental in yoga philosophy
when we practice prāṇāyāma and meditation, we purify the chitta
the ultimate goal is moksha, liberation from the cycle of samsara
as taught in the Upaniṣads, tat tvam asi, thou art that
through sadhana and devotion to guru, we realize our true nature as ātman