Um, today we will discuss, uh, I mean we'll explore the Bhagavad Gita chapter two verse twenty five.
This verse, you know, actually this verse talks about the eternal nature of the soul.
Let me rephrase that, the soul is described as imperishable and eternal.
Krishna explains, rather, he reveals the true nature of the atman in this teaching.
The the soul cannot be cut by weapons, and and it cannot be burned by fire.
What I meant was, the soul is beyond physical destruction entirely.
Now, this is a fundamental teaching, so we must understand its significance.
Well, this concept appears in verse twenty seven as well, um, if I recall correctly.
The ancient sages understood this truth, and and they passed it down through generations.
So, what this means, you see, is that consciousness is eternal and unchanging.