Today we will discuss, explore the Bhagavad Gita chapter 2 verse 25.
This verse, this verse talks about the eternal nature of the soul.
That, the soul is described as imperishable and eternal.
Kṛṣṇa explains, he reveals the true nature of the ātman in this teaching.
The soul cannot be cut by weapons, and it cannot be burned by fire.
What t was, the soul is beyond physical destruction
This is a fundamental teaching, so we must understand its significance.
Well, this concept appears in verse 27 as if I recall correctly.
The ancient sages understood this truth, and they passed it down through generations.
What this means, is that consciousness is eternal and unchanging.