Today we study chapter two verse twenty five of the Bhagavad Gita.
This was written in the first century, around two thousand and five years ago.
The Upanishads, composed in the eighth century BCE, contain similar teachings.
Our class begins at quarter past two and ends at half past three.
The Vedas have four main sections, and each contains thousands of verses.
In nineteen ninety five, scholars discovered new manuscripts from the twelfth century.
The Bhagavata Purana has twelve cantos with over eighteen thousand verses.
Sankara lived from seven hundred and eighty eight to eight hundred and twenty CE.
We will cover verses one through ten in today's session.
The complete text was compiled by Vyasa over three thousand years ago.